Oh my name is green and welcome back to
another episode of hermitcraft
I'm down here with bill and I think it's
gonna be Ted I have I still haven't
named this fella but basically I'm
trying to stock up on as many emeralds
as possible because hermit craft is
currently in a bit of a stage of waiting
we're waiting for 1.14 to hit the server
obviously 1.14 is already out the new
update to minecraft but it's kind of
buggy especially for servers maybe not
single-player so much but for servers
there's a lot of issues so we're kind of
waiting on that which I'm not
complaining about because this is
probably my last chance to get a lot of
emeralds with the setup that I have
there's probably new ways to to farm
them but not in the way that I've got
here so I don't think when 114 comes out
that my destroyer of worlds my eater of
universes are gonna continue farming in
fact I think they're just gonna sit in
the tube and do nothing I cannot
guarantee that these guys are gonna
continue farming for me at least this
will keep working and the pumpkin farm
will keep working but 114 I think is
going to break my trading system so I'm
just gonna speed through this and trade
as much as possible for until I run out
of crops and that looks like pretty much
all of it now I didn't actually get that
many emeralds from it but I have got a
decent amount I'll just have to continue
farming these for the next couple of
days while we wait for 114 and then I'm
gonna have to set these guys into the
wild you guys can be free yeah
fortunately for me I don't think I'm
gonna have that many bits of farm or
anything that I've made that's gonna
break too much because mostly I've been
focusing on the building and oh my word
look at this I only saw this bit and I
thought this was gonna be a rocket it
kind of is but look at that scar that's
amazing
this is puts my
my little platform to shame mum bus has
I built an ugly minecart tube oh dear
let's go and have a look why did we put
him in charge of making anything I see
I can I can immediately see what the
issue is he's got way too many of these
rings around it does he want some help
or I might leave the pretty bit for
another day I think all he's got to do
is take out this one every other one
needs to go and then it will look much
better
so this tube for people that don't know
actually this is a good point
some people don't actually know what
Sahara is and that baffles me because
we've been making and building Sahara
for like a few months now and people
still don't know what it is Sahara is a
shop but it's bigger and better than any
of the shops in the shopping district
because most of these yeah you go in
them you go to what you need you put the
diamonds in and you just take it out
with Sahara we will stock as much as we
can and then you go here this is like
the shop front you come in here and then
you select what you want it does like
some magic where it throws and so you
like press key on this it throws it in
here there's some like hoppers and stuff
under there it tells the system back
here what you ordered and then and this
is the really clever part it sends a
signal all the ways for exactly the
amount that you want into our warehouse
and all of the items are stored in here
it then collects all the items puts it
in a shulker box for you sends it along
this tube that mumbo is trying to make
and then back out to the customer so in
15 seconds you can have everything that
you need or want or ordered from here
into your hands instead of having to go
to every shop in the shopping district
and it's going to be cheaper and you get
a schalke box with every single order so
that's going to be that's basically
Sahara and I need to add some things
here that will keep them entertained
while they wait for just 15 seconds 15
seconds is not a lot but this is unique
I've never seen anything like this on my
craft but when it comes to the redstone
I don't know anything I don't know I
don't really know how it works I don't
like the idea and stuff I just I just
build the stuff okay but unfortunately
because this is so unique and it's so
complicated the amount of resources that
have gone into this is absolutely insane
and that's without even starting to
stock the stuff I have actually been
working on collecting some sand a lot of
it so here's a quick time-lapse of me
collecting sand from a desert it's not
actually that much but you'll see that
I've done pretty well in terms I think
it's only like half an hour's worth of
grinding but take a look at this this is
the spoils of my time-lapse shelcha box
schalke box after shoka box full of sand
to add on to my other sand that I've got
in here basically Sahara is gonna have a
lot of sand but sand isn't the only
thing that Sahara needs we actually need
and this this made me this made me like
throw up a little bit in my mouth when
this gal told me this I did not know
this when I started this project I
didn't know that we would need this may
shock our boxes this gal told me that we
need 1400 shoka boxes yet you have 1400
schalke boxes that is an insane those
hours and hours and hours of end busting
so I'm actually gonna team I'm team up
with Ren dog who isn't actually part of
Sahara but he needs to do some end
busting as well so we're gonna team up
and go end busting together it's gonna
be a long long long jaunt so hopefully
I'm just gonna put in some of the the
highlights of our little adventure so
time to meet up with Ren Greene my
friend hi hello and the doge man have
you ever just stared into the void yes
and I've even I've made a room that's
like entirely that because there's like
a secret block you can use and its
content stop I'm gonna contemplate
existence too long right yeah we're
gonna go sting right yeah
and busting I need a bunch of shelcha
boxes because
well actually I just need a video cuz
I'm going on holiday with my parents so
okay well I actually need schalke boxes
[Laughter]
that's a long way down
oh oh look at him I might have I might I
might have looked at somebody I've got a
bit of a problem to deal with first
we're not off to a good start yet
well I thought my screen had gone nuts
then but it's just the world border do I
die if I go into this I think you just
bounce off it no I went straight through
it yeah you can go on the other side
slightly Oh big city big and city
alright we leave the ship to last right
sure is that how we do is that how we do
yeah okay I know you said leave the boat
to last
are you are you there already it already
oh yeah that was the first thing I did
when shooting for the boat straight down
Elektra you won't forget it all
[Music]
dibs electro this is the biggie
where's where is the boat on the other
side alright should we head to this
other that NCD I think we're done here
if they're I'm not hunting them down but
alright you get that one I'm gonna get
the electron oh no no no no you've got
too much of a head start on me the thing
is you know exactly where to dig down is
it is it here if pop ran yes
help where are you up here
nope oh geez I win [\h__\h] yeah
right is that a lingering oh no dude
mistakes have been made
I've thrown an ender pearl into the void
this is bad no you haven't
No all right I don't know what to do for
you no you didn't you're fine
it still might be dropping though well
try and put all your stuff in your in
the chest no dude it's okay okay
Enderman was trying to kill me can't we
just meet on the boat please before I
literally have a heart attack yeah I
mean I I have the same problem with the
Enderman
can't we just can I just take a moment
to return my heart from my throat in
tomorrow yeah okay dude you ready we're
gonna breathe in mistake mistake Randy
he's gonna kill me got it got him
Endemol of the worst thing they've ever
made
Teddy time and then we get in the heck
out of here money's right I'm gonna put
mine in the left hand chest okay
somebody attended already yeah the big
reveal yeah all right all right you're
right you got two stacks of chakra
shells plus twelve eleven diamonds and a
few gems you got loads of shoulders
skulls and one Electra not too bad yeah
not too bad if I do say so myself
Brando come back come back we said we'd
split it 50/50 remember Wow dude you did
so good let's split the diamonds in half
cuz that's alright you know that's fair
and you take one of the Electra oops
that's a bit yeah
you can have the other 12 chakra shots
to codes around numbers of all right so
G we need to get home man
the fastest way to go is you know just
kill yourself and you end up back at
your spawn in India so I know you said
no earlier but can we play chicken now
because it doesn't matter if you die you
mean as in pay check with the bottom of
Minecraft yes so basically what we're
gonna do we're gonna jump we're going it
with our light show with one of these
Elijah that we got in the in the end
busting and you have to see how low you
can get without dying okay and the
person well this doesn't make sense if
we're both gonna die oh yeah totally
does it make sense well we'll do it
anyway we'll try and try and live and
see who can get the lowest and yeah
right so if you die you lose so it's
about yeah if it's trying to get the
lowest if you die you lose I don't know
what y-coordinate we actually start
taking damage so the goal right is okay
you have to dive as low as possible
mm-hmm if you don't survive you lose so
even if I just jumped off here and right
straight back up but you died I would
win even if I got a terrible score okay
I shall we just call this a science
experiment this is a science experiment
so I'm gonna fly down as soon okay okay
- is lots of viruses okay he went like
minus 10 and I chickened out so early
whoops I was so convinced that you would
just start taking damage the second you
went into the - but that makes no sense
you know so you lose because you didn't
chicken out I mean you're brave man but
yeah yeah I won with a terrible score so
that's got to feel bad I don't
don't feel good I'm not sure you don't
feel good either no I've yeah about 90
yeah you can't fly out very easily
yeah that's what happens to be it's
about minus 90 yeah well that brings end
busting to an end well now that we've
done a bit of end busting and a bit of
sand collecting the stock the Sahara is
actually going up including some
contribution to the Shockers that are
going to be needed in even a couple of
elektra as well although I might
actually use these for my electric
course if people need them perhaps and
then all of this will be used later on
for the did you die boxes speaking of
the electric course why don't I show you
the progress that I've made cuz I've
spent a couple of hours really thinking
about where I'm going to go and I even
had a meeting with false and cub to talk
about how it could go through their
bases they gave me the positions and
I've got ahead and implemented them so
we're only going to go through this once
so pay attention we've already done many
of the starting points and I'm going to
work out how many Rockets you're gonna
need so I don't want people basically
holding down rockets to keep up a big
speed so I might limit them to a stack
of rockets per go and that's one of the
worries if you hit your head and it kind
it doesn't damage you but it delays you
that could affect your time as well
you've got to go through that there's a
really difficult ring to get through
you've got to go down through here this
is some of the new rings here I've
actually made a bigger one they're just
sort of sticking out of the ground to
make it a bit more interesting implement
here now I did say I would go through
this Canyon and I have made the Rings to
go through them there's actually quite a
few of them you continue there's the
final wooden one and then we enter
Concord now everything from this point
on I did have a meeting with KUB and he
told me to go straight through here
round the back so it doesn't go anywhere
near his main builds through here and
then turn left so we're not actually
going through the middle of Concord
which is totally understandable but the
course does go right round
it and you get to make good use of this
big orange thing which is actually
really cool I wanted to be able to use
this so Cub suggested that I go through
here then left and then we're out of
Concord and what I've done here I'm
actually quite impressed with myself
here because this I think this is quite
clever I've basically elongated one of
these tags here I've just slightly
altered it and it sticks out just under
just enough space for someone to fly
through so you turn through you go
through this hoop here and then all
you've got to do is through there but
that's a very tricky one because you can
hit your head so you've kind of got to
go at a bit of speed rock it straight
down and then that's as far as I've got
I can't tell you how many fireworks I've
gotten through testing this so far it's
been manic more Rockets than usual but
this is as far as I've got so far and
now I need to work out where I'm going
to go so I spoke to false and the
general consensus was to go somewhere
through here and then to the left
through the skeleton of wrens dragon now
that's quite a cool things it's gonna be
a difficult fly to get through there
without injuring yourself at all so if I
through wrens dragon and then we're
gonna pass through her forest which is
where she said to make one of the flight
points and then we're home free
on to the finish point now the finish
point as we know we said right at the
start of making this Electra course
would be at my base so I've somehow got
to make points of interest and make it a
difficult flight from the dragon all the
way through here and maybe in and about
here I can create some rings this is
quite a barren landscape here so there's
nothing too much to be interfering with
but the end of it was meant to be at the
top of here like one big ring up there
but whether that's hey wait wait a
minute there's loads of cows here now oh
my I know I mean I know how this has
happened oh this is hilarious so I
didn't care did it get rid of all the
cows oh no these any mobs are going to
cause a bit of lag but that is really
funny Oh
no no I'm sorry and this is Eva chickens
were seriously I need to make sure okay
so if you're confused how that's
happened I know exactly how this has
happened so when I was breeding all
those cows a little while ago in here
some of them just basically wandered
into this this tube this tube and
they've just gone straight up all the
way to the top bless them
I'm surprised they didn't drown wow it
really is a long way up and then some of
them didn't make it out at all how many
are in here
Betsey's it Betsy and Bertie Oh No to be
honest with you I wa I wasn't planning
on keeping them I'm sorry everyone look
away from the screen I'm gonna look away
I'm sorry I'm sorry
they're all gone it's it's for the
server's sake that is really funny so
that is how all of these cows managed to
get out so before we were interrupted by
the cow apocalypse I was saying that the
end of the alight course should be up
here I'm just not sure how to I'm gonna
have to make rings going like through
there and then maybe oh I could even
make the player of the electric horse
fly upwards through here as a final test
you've got to fly all the way through
the base through there do a double-take
and go around to the final ring but I
think that's pretty much where the
electrical is gonna go I did actually
think very carefully about having all of
the electricals go all over the island
but at the end of the day I don't want
it to be too long or too complex I just
one big circle I think is more than
enough it takes over a minute and a half
as it is so that's yeah I think that's
more than enough so unfortunately this
side of the island kind of misses out
wait what is it with all the mobs around
here now last time I picked up a jack
skeleton it didn't end well for him
I think I'm gonna have to just leave you
there because I can't I can't get enough
I can't get attached to another skeleton
horse so I think that is all we have
time for today I know that we're kind of
waiting for 114 and I feel like quite a
few other people are as well seeing as
I've been the only one on the server all
day kind of feels that way but I'm
hoping that 114 will which is the new
Minecraft update if anybody is unaware
of that it is going to be absolutely
epic and I have a big plan
for 114 of course we are going to finish
Sahara but I'm hoping that we can make a
little venture little adventure and
create an outpost into the new 1.14
areas maybe find ourselves a village and
do some things there so that would be
really really cool but until then the
episodes on hermitcraft might be a
little bit slower as we're not sure when
114 is going to be bug free and able to
be put on hermitcraft just yet so bear
with me
and we'll be back when 114 hits or maybe
not it depends how long it is thank you
very much for watching as always and
goodbye